<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
    ────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────── copyright and license ───

    File: data/tapper.metainfo.xml

    Copyright 🄯 2014, 2016—2017, 2019—2023 Van de Bugger.

    This file is part of Tapper.

    Copying and distribution of this file, with or without modification, are permitted in any
    medium without royalty provided the copyright notice and this notice are preserved. This file
    is offered as-is, without any warranty.

    SPDX-License-Identifier: FSFAP

    ────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────── copyright and license ───
-->
<component>
    <id>@PACKAGE_ID@</id> <!-- TODO: Replace hyphen in id with underscore. -->
    <name>@PACKAGE_NAME@</name>
    <name lang="ru">Таппер</name>
    <summary>@PACKAGE_SUMMARY@</summary>
    <icon type="stock">input-keyboard</icon>
    <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">@PACKAGE_ID@.desktop</launchable>
    <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
    <description>
        <p>
            Tapper is a keyboard layout switcher for X Window System and Wayland. Tapper runs in
            background, when an assigned key is tapped, Tapper activates the corresponding keyboard
            layout. Tapper key feature is using modifier keys for switching keyboard layouts
            without losing modifier’s functionality. Tapper works for GNOME, GNOME Classic,
            Cinnamon, i3, KDE, LXDE, LXQt, Mate, Ubuntu, Xfce desktops.
        </p>
        <p>
            A <em>tap</em> means that a single key is pressed and quickly released, so: (1) no
            other keys are pressed or released at this time, and (2) period between pressing the
            key and releasing it is shorter than keyboard repeat delay (the amount of time you have
            to hold down a key before it starts repeating; usually 0.5 second, but it depends on
            your desktop settings).︎
        </p>
        <p lang="ru">
            Таппер — включалка раскладок клавиатуры для Иксов и Вайланда. Таппер работает в фоновом
            режиме, и при ударе по назначенной клавише Таппер включает соответствующую ей раскладку
            клавиатуры. Особенность Таппера заключается в использовании клавиш-модификаторов для
            включения раскладок без потери функций модификаторов. Таппер работает в Гноме,
            Классическом Гноме, и3, КДЕ, ЛХДЕ, ЛХКт, Мате, Хфце, Циннамоне.
        </p>
        <p lang="ru">
            <em>Удар</em> — нажатие и быстрое отпускание одной клавиши, при этом: (1) во время
            удара никакие другие клавиши не нажаты, не нажимаются и не отпускаются, и (2) период
            между нажатием и отпусканием короче задержки автоповтора (обычно автоповтор включается
            если клавиша удерживается более половины секунды; это зависит от настроек рабочего
            стола).
        </p>
        <p lang="ru">
            «Удар» по-английски — <em>tap</em>. Отсюда происходит название программы.
        </p>
    </description>
    <categories>
        <category>System</category>
        <category>Utility</category>
    </categories>
    <keywords>
        <keyword>keyboard layout</keyword>
        <keyword>keyboard layout switcher</keyword>
        <keyword lang="ru">раскладка клавиатуры</keyword>
        <keyword lang="ru">включалка раскладок клавиатуры</keyword>
    </keywords>
    <url type="homepage">@PACKAGE_URL@</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">@PACKAGE_URL@bugs.html</url>
    <url type="help" lang="en">@PACKAGE_URL@tapper.en.html</url>
    <!-- url type="help" lang="ru">@PACKAGE_URL@tapper.ru.html</url -->
    <provides>
        <binary>@bindir@/@name@</binary>
    </provides>
    <recommends>
        <id>ca.desrt.dconf-editor.desktop</id>
        <control>keyboard</control>
    </recommends>
@RELEASES@
</component>

<!-- end of file -->
